Guide to the William E. Irwin Photograph Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Arizona, circa 1904-1945; Series II; 1.25; (1 box)
  - Unidentified Locations in Arizona
    - View of a desert landscape with Carnegiea gigantea (saguaro) cactus from a highway between Phoenix and Globe in Arizona, circa 1904-1945; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 2, Folder 248)
      Inscription on verso: "Views along the highway between Phoenix and Globe"
    - View of cattle in a stream between railroad tracks and highway in Arizona, circa 1904-1945 (Box 2, Folder 249)
      Inscription on verso: "Views along the highway between Nogales and Tucson"
    - View of a desert landscape with Carnegiea gigantea (saguaro) cactus in Arizona, circa 1904-1945; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 2, Folder 250)
    - View of a dirt road among conifer trees in Arizona, circa 1904-1945; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 2, Folder 251)
    - Exterior portrait of three men posed standing and crouching with four hunting dogs, as well as the carcasses of three puma hanging from the gate of a corral in Arizona, circa 1904-1945; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 2, Folder 252)
    - View of four men pulling a puma from a tree with a rope in Arizona, circa 1904-1945; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 2, Folder 253)
    - View of three men placing a lasso around a puma in a tree in Arizona, circa 1904-1945; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 2, Folder 254)
    - Exterior portrait of three men posed standing with two hunting dogs, as well as the carcasses of three puma hanging from the gate of a corral in Arizona, circa 1904-1945; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 255)
    - View of a desert landscape with Carnegiea gigantea (saguaro) cactus in Arizona, circa 1904-1945 (Box 2, Folder 256)
      1 unmounted photographic print
      Inscription in negative: "Along the country roads of Southern Ariz., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of a desert landscape with Carnegiea gigantea (saguaro) cactus in Arizona, circa 1904-1945 (Box 2, Folder 257)
      Inscription in negative: "Typical desert scene in Southern Ariz., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of a desert landscape with Carnegiea gigantea (saguaro) cactus in Arizona, circa 1904-1945; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 258)
      Inscription in negative: "Some of the Wonders of Southern Ariz., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of a desert landscape with Carnegiea gigantea (saguaro) cactus along the highway between Tucson and Phoenix in Arizona, circa 1904-1945 (Box 2, Folder 259)
      Inscription in negative: "Desert scenes along the Tucson Phoenix Highway, Ariz., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of a desert landscape with Carnegiea gigantea (saguaro) cactus in Arizona, circa 1904-1945 (Box 2, Folder 260)
      Inscription in negative: "In the heart of the desert, Southern Ariz., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of a desert landscape with Carnegiea gigantea (saguaro) cactus in Arizona, circa 1904-1945 (Box 2, Folder 261)
      Inscription in negative: "On the deserts of Southern Ariz., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of a rolling landscape with mountains in the background, probably in Arizona, circa 1904-1945 (Box 2, Folder 262)
    - View of a desert landscape with Opuntia (nopales or paddle) cactus in Arizona, circa 1904-1945 (Box 2, Folder 263)
    - View of a cactus in southern Arizona, circa 1904-1945 (Box 2, Folder 264)
      Inscription in negative: "Barrel Cactus of Southern Ariz... ." a portion of the inscription obscured
    - View of men and children standing near barrels on a dirt road with wooden house, probably in Arizona, possibly related to Prohibition of alcohol, circa 1920 (Box 2, Folder 264a)
    - View of a man, identified as possibly Marvin Elmore Irwin, with an automobile and a wall tent among trees, probably in Arizona, circa 1925; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 2, Folder 264b)
    - View of a desert landscape with Carnegiea gigantea (saguaro) cactus in southern Arizona, circa 1904-1945; 1 unmounted photographic print
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 14, folder 916
      Inscription in negative: "A typical cactus forest of Southern Ariz., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of a desert landscape with Carnegiea gigantea (saguaro) cactus in southern Arizona, circa 1904-1945; 1 unmounted photographic print
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 14, folder 917
      Inscription in negative: "Typical desert scenes in Southern Ariz., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of a desert landscape with Yucca brevifolia (yucca palm or Joshua Tree) in Arizona, circa 1904-1945; 1 unmounted photographic print, hand colored
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 14, folder 918
    - View of a desert landscape with mountains in the distance, probably in Arizona, circa 1904-1945; 1 unmounted photographic print, hand colored
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 14, folder 919
- California, 1927-1944; Series III; 0.21; (1 box)
  Arranged chronologically.
  This series consists of groups of informal photographs that chiefly document tourist trips to California, probably by members of the extended Irwin family.
  - Views of Grauman's Chinese Theatre in Hollywood, California, 1927 July 27-August; 3 unmounted photographic prints and 1 photographic postcard (Box 3, Folder 265)
    Inscriptions on versos
    Ink stamp on versos of prints: "199"
  - Views of the Honeyville Restaurant in Duarte, California, as well as the clubhouse for the Lake Luring Country Club in Running Springs, and boats on the Big Bear Lake reservoir in Big Bear Lake, 1927 July 30; 8 unmounted photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 266)
    Ink stamp on versos of most prints: "363"
  - View of Santa Catalina Island, including views of glass bottom boats, ferry boats, and Hotel Mac Rae, 1927 August 5; 7 unmounted photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 267)
    Inscriptions on versos of prints: "185"
  - Views of Los Angeles, California, including views of the Angelus Temple of the International Church of the Foursquare Gospel and a view of a curving railroad on the Mount Lowe Railway, as well as a view of ships near the Balboa Peninsula, 1927 August; 4 unmounted photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 268)
    Ink stamp on versos of prints: "129"
  - Views of the Torrey Pines Lodge in the community of La Jolla in San Diego, California, 1927 September 1; 2 photographic negatives and 3 unmounted photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 269)
    Ink stamp on versos of prints: "32"
  - View of a path in Balboa Park in San Diego, California, 1927 September 2; 1 photographic negative and 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 270)
  - Views of Sunset Cliffs Park in the Sunset Cliffs neighborhood of the Point Loma community in San Diego, California, 1927 September 2; 3 photographic negatives and 3 unmounted photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 271)
  - View of view of the ruins of the "Great Stone Church" at Mission San Juan Capistrano, California, circa 1927 September; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 3, Folder 272)
  - View of a people at a beach, possibly in San Diego, as well as a view of a burro hitched to a wooden wagon, possibly in Tijuana, Mexico, circa 1927 September; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 273)
    Ink stamp on versos of prints: "A14"
  - View of the Long Beach Municipal Pier, including a portion of The Pike amusement zone and adjoining beach, in Long Beach, California, 1931; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 274)
    1 photographic print is an enlargement of the view
  - Views of Horace Mann Junior High School in San Diego, California, 1944; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 275)
    Inscription on versos: "Horace Mann Jr. Hi. School, San Diego, 1944, Gone"
    Ink stamp on versos of prints: "290"
- Colorado, circa 1904-1935; Series IV; 0.21; (1 box)
  Series IV is organized into three subseries: Garden of the Gods, Ouray, and Telluride
  This series chiefly consists of landscape views of sites in Colorado.
  - Garden of the Gods
    - View of a dirt road through rock formations at Garden of the Gods, west of Colorado Springs, Colorado, circa 1904-1935; 1 mounted photographic print and 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 4, Folder 276)
      Inscription in negative of a print: "In the Garden of the Gods, Colorado Springs, Colo., Photo by Ed Irwin"
      Inscription on recto of a print: "Views around Manitou, Colo."
    - View of the Cathedral Spires sandstone rock formations in Garden of the Gods, west of Colorado Springs, Colorado, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 4, Folder 277)
      Inscription in negative: "In the Garden of the Gods, Colorado Springs, Colo., Photo by Ed Irwin"
      Ink inscription on verso: "By Ed Irwin, 1702 E. 1st St., Tucson, Ariz., Picture #9"
    - View of the Cathedral Spires sandstone rock formations in Garden of the Gods, west of Colorado Springs, Colorado, circa 1904-1935; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 4, Folder 278)
      Inscription on recto: "Views around Colorado Springs, Colo."
    - View of Balanced Rock, a sandstone rock formation in Garden of the Gods, west of Colorado Springs, Colorado, circa 1904-1935; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 4, Folder 279)
      Inscription on recto: "Balance Rock near Manitou, Colo."
  - Ouray
    - Overhead view of Ouray, Colorado, including Hayden Mountain and Abrams Mountain, circa 1904-1935; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 4, Folder 280)
      Inscription in negative: "Ouray, Colo., looking south"
    - View of snow-covered buildings, as well as a pipe on a wooden trestle, near Ouray, Colorado, circa 1904-1935; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 4, Folder 281)
      Inscription on recto: "Winter scenes in Euray, Colo."
    - View of snow-covered buildings, as well as a pipe on a wooden trestle, near Ouray, Colorado, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 4, Folder 282)
      Inscription in negative: "Mid-Winter Scenes around Ouray, Colo., Photo by Ed Irwin"
    - View of frozen waterfalls below a wooden truss bridge near Ouray, Colorado, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 4, Folder 283)
      Inscription on recto: "Winter Time Scenes around Ouray, Colo., Photo by Ed Irwin"
    - View of two wagon teams on a dirt road in a mountain valley near Ouray, Colorado, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 4, Folder 284)
      Inscription in negative: "Along the mountain roads around Ouray, Colo., Photo by Ed Irwin"
      Ink stamp on verso of a print: "Irwin's Studio, Silver City, N.M."
    - View of a train of donkeys loaded with ore near Ouray, Colorado, circa 1904-1935; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 4, Folder 285)
      Inscription on verso of a print: "Ore pack in Colo., Ouray"
  - Telluride
    - View of a donkey train loaded with planks of wood on a trail to the Tomboy Mine east of Telluride, Colorado, 1904-1927; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 4, Folder 286)
      Inscription in negative of a print: "Along the Tomboy Trail near Telluride, Colo., Irwin"
      Inscription in negative of a print: "Photo by Irwin, Bisbee, Ariz."
    - View of a donkey train loaded with planks of wood on a trail to the Tomboy Mine, which is visible in the distance, east of Telluride, Colorado Around the Tomboy Mine near Telluride, Colorado - donkey train carrying lumber, 1904-1927; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 4, Folder 287)
      Inscription in negative: "Around the Tomboy Mine near Telluride, Colo., Photo by Ed Irwin"
    - View of a donkey train on a trail to the Tomboy Mine east of Telluride, Colorado "Views around Telluride, Colorado" - donkey train carrying bundles and boxes, 1904-1927; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 4, Folder 288)
      Inscription in negative: "Views around Telluride, Colo., Photo by Irwin, Bisbee, Ariz."
- Mexico, 1907-1913; Series V; 0.21; (1 box)
  Series V is organized into four subseries: Naco, Sonora; Sierra Madre Occidental; Mexican-American Border Region; and Unidentified Locations in Mexico
  This series chiefly consists of images related to a hunting party in the Sierra Madre Occidental mountains in November 1907, and the Mexican Revolution, 1910-1913.
  - Naco, Sonora
    - View of men observing the Battle of Naco in Mexico during the Mexican Revolution through a gap between railcars from the El Paso and Southwestern Railroad loaded with coal, 1913 April; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 5, Folder 289)
      Inscription on recto: "Watching battle through coke cars from U.S. side, Naco, Sonora"
    - View of buildings in Naco, Sonora, burning during the Battle of Naco during the Mexican Revolution, 1913 April; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 5, Folder 290)
      Inscription on recto: "Naco burning during battle"
    - View of Mexican men, identified as Constitutionalists following the Battle of Naco during the Mexican Revolution, and horses outside of a building identified as the commissary in Naco, Sonora, 1913 April; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 5, Folder 291)
      Inscription on recto: "Rebels carrying in supplies from the rear after the battle, Naco, Sonora. Sacks of sand on top of building used for breastworks during battle."
    - View of men and boys near the ruins of buildings, including a customs agent building, in Naco, Sonora, following the Battle of Naco, circa 1913 April; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 5, Folder 292)
      Inscription on recto: "The Federal's last stand, This burnt building is 30 feet from U.S. boundary line. Charred body lying to right of picture by grate. Naco, Sonora"
    - Exterior portrait of Álvaro Obregón Salido by a brick building, probably in Naco, Sonora, circa 1913 April; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 5, Folder 293)
      Inscription on recto: "General Obregón, who led the rebels to victory at Naco Sonora"
  - Sierra Madre Occidental
    - Exterior portrait of four men posed standing in camp with ten deer carcasses hanging from a stand in a forest, near the Sierra Madre Occidental mountains near Chihuahua, Mexico, 1907 November; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 5, Folder 294)
      Inscription in negative: "Hunting party in the Sierra Madre Mts, Chihuahua, Mex., Photo by Ed Irwin"
    - Exterior portrait of four men, including William Edward "Ed" Irwin on the left, posed standing in camp with ten deer carcasses hanging from a stand in a forest, Sierra Madre Occidental mountains near Chihuahua, Mexico, 1907 November; 2 mounted photographic prints, and 5 unmounted photographic prints, including 1 hand colored print (Box 5, Folder 295)
      Inscription in negative of an unmounted print: "Hunting party in the Sierra Madre Mts., Chihuahua, Mex., Photo by Ed Irwin"
      Inscription on the recto of a mounted print: "Hunting party in the Siera Madre Mts., Mex. Nov' 07"
      Blind-stamp on the recto of the mounted prints and one unmounted print: "Irwin, Bisbee, Arizona"
      Inscription on the verso of the hand colored print: "By Era Bock, Mch 2, 1926"
      Two unmounted photographic prints, including the hand colored print, are details of the image
    - Exterior portrait of four men, including William Edward "Ed" Irwin second from the left, posed sitting in camp with ten deer carcasses on the ground, Sierra Madre Occidental mountains near Chihuahua, Mexico, 1907 November; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 5, Folder 296)
      Inscription on recto: "Hunting camp in the Siera Madre Mts., Mex. Nov' 07"
      Blind-stamp on recto: "Irwin, Bisbee, Arizona"
    - Exterior portrait of four men posed standing with eight horses in a forest, Sierra Madre Occidental mountains near Chihuahua, Mexico, 1907 November; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 5, Folder 297)
      Inscription on recto: "Hunting party in the Siera Madre Mts., Mex. Nov' 07"
    - Exterior portrait of a man, identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin, posed reclining on the ground of a forest with two deer carcasses, Sierra Madre Occidental mountains near Chihuahua, Mexico, 1907 November; 2 mounted photographic prints (Box 5, Folder 298)
      Inscription on recto: "Deer hunting in the Siera Madre Mts., Mex. Nov' 07"
      Blind-stamp on rectos: "Irwin, Bisbee, Arizona"
    - Exterior view of two deers carcasses on the ground of a forest, Sierra Madre Occidental mountains near Chihuahua, Mexico, 1907 November; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 5, Folder 299)
      Inscription on recto: "Specimens of the whitetail deer in Chihuahua, Mex."
    - View of cliff dwellings, probably Cuarenta Casas in the Sierra Madre Occidental, Mexico, 1907 November; 2 mounted photographic prints (Box 5, Folder 300)
      Inscription on rectos: "Cliff dweller ruins in Siera Madre Mts., Mex."
  - Mexican-American Border Region
    - Exterior portrait of two men, man on left identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin, posed standing with rifles with a puma over Irwin's shoulder and a deer carcass on the ground, in the Mexican-American Border region, 1910 November; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 5, Folder 301)
      Inscription in negative: "Hunting along the border of Ariz. & Mex., Photo by Ed Irwin"
      Inscription on verso: "By Ed Irwin, 1702 E. 1st St., Tucson, Ariz., Picture #15"
    - Exterior portrait of a man, identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin, and a woman, identified as probably Carrie Matilda "Tillie" Allen Irwin, posed kneeling with rifles near the carcasses of two pumas in the Mexican-American Border region, 1910 November; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 5, Folder 302)
      Inscription in negative of a print: "Lion hunting along the border of Ariz. & Mex., Photo by Ed Irwin"
    - Exterior portrait of a woman, identified as probably Carrie Matilda "Tillie" Allen Irwin, posed sitting on a log with rifle and looking through binoculars, near the carcasses of two pumas in the Mexican-American Border region, 1910 November; 4 unmounted photographic prints (Box 5, Folder 303)
      Inscription in negative of two prints: "Lion hunting along the Mexican border., Photo by Ed Irwin"
    - Exterior portrait of an African American soldier in the United States Army soldier posed standing with a rifle next to a pile of firearms and ammunition, probably in the Mexican-American Border region, circa 1910; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 5, Folder 304)
    - Exterior portrait of Venustiano Carranza de la Garza posed sitting and surrounded by three women and nine men posed standing, probably in the Mexican-American Border Region, circa 1913-1915; 1 mounted photographic print
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 14, folder 920
      Blind-stamp on recto: "M. Irwin, Douglas, Ariz."
    - Exterior portrait of a man, identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin, and a woman, identified as probably Carrie Matilda "Tillie" Allen Irwin, posed kneeling with rifles near the carcasses of two pumas in the Mexican-American Border region, 1910 November; 1 mounted photographic print
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 14, folder 921
      Inscription on recto: "Lion hunting along the border of Arizona & Mex., Nov. 1910"
    - Exterior portrait of a woman, identified as probably Carrie Matilda "Tillie" Allen Irwin, posed sitting on a log with rifle and looking through binoculars, near the carcasses of two pumas in the Mexican-American Border region, 1910 November; 1 mounted photographic print
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 14, folder 922
      Inscription on recto: "Hunting the mountain lion in Arizona, Nov. 1910"
    - Exterior portrait of two men, man on left identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin, posed standing with rifles with a puma over Irwin's shoulder and a deer carcass on the ground, in the Mexican-American Border region, 1910 November; 1 mounted photographic print
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 14, folder 923
      Inscription on recto: "Deer & lion hunting along the border of Arizona & Mex., Nov. 1910"
    - Exterior portrait of a man, identified as William Edward "Ed" Irwin, and a woman, identified as probably Carrie Matilda "Tillie" Allen Irwin, with their backs to the camera and each carrying a puma carcass over their shoulder and holding rifles in the Mexican-American Border region, 1910 November; 1 mounted photographic print
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 14, folder 924
    - Exterior portrait of two men from behind posed mounted on two horses with two pack donkeys on a dirt trail, probably in the Mexican-American Border Region, circa 1910; 1 mounted photographic print
      Stored in: Oversize, Box 14, folder 925
      Inscription on recto: "U. S. line riders along the border of Arizona & Mex., Nov. 1910"
  - Unidentified Locations in Mexico
    - View of two men posed standing with four donkeys loaded with two barrels each in front of a building, probably in Mexico, circa 1910-1913; 1 mounted photographic print (Box 5, Folder 305)
      Inscription on verso: "Burros loaded with mescal"
    - Exterior portrait of a man mounted on a horse and aiming a rifle in a desert landscape, probably in Mexico, circa 1910-1913; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 5, Folder 306)
- New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; Series VI; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Series VI is organized into eighteen subseries: Apache Box, City of Rocks, Fort Bayard, Gila River, Grant County, Kneeling Nun, Mescalero, Mimbres River, Needle's Eye, Needle's Eye, Pinos Altos, Sacramento Mountains, Santa Rita, Silver City, Steeple Rock, Sylvanite, Tyrone, Unidentified Locations in New Mexico, and Photocollages of New Mexico Sites
  This series chiefly consists of landscape views of sites throughout New Mexico, as well as views of ranches, highways, and mining operations.
  - Apache Box
    - View of horses in a corral at the ranch of William Edward "Ed" Irwin near Apache Box, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 4 photographic postcards and 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 6, Folder 307)
      Inscription in negative of four postcards and the print: "Cow Ponies of Southwestern N.M., Photo by Irwin"
      Pencil inscription on verso of a photographic postcard: "W. E. Irwin's horses in corral near Apache Box, N.M."
      Two photographic postcards printed reversed
      An unmounted print is a detail of the image
    - View of horses in a corral at the ranch of William Edward "Ed" Irwin near Apache Box, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 308)
      Inscription on recto: "Saddle horses on our New Mex. ranch"
    - View of horses in a corral at the ranch of William Edward "Ed" Irwin near Apache Box, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 309)
    - View of horses in a corral at the ranch of William Edward "Ed" Irwin near Apache Box, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 6, Folder 310)
      Inscription in negative: "Saddle horses in the Silver City Country, N.M., Photo by Irwin"
      Inscription on verso: "Mr E Irwin's sadle horses"
  - City of Rocks
    - Rock formations of City of Rocks near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 311)
      Inscription in negative: "In the City of Rocks, near Silver City, N. M., Photo by Irwin"
    - Rock formations of City of Rocks near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 2 unmounted photographic prints (Box 6, Folder 312)
      Inscription in negative: "Around the City of Rocks, near Silver City, N. M., Photo by Irwin"
    - Rock formations of City of Rocks near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 unmounted photographic print (Box 6, Folder 313)
      Inscription in negative: "City of Rocks, near Silver City, N. M., Photo by Irwin"
    - View of a rock formation, probably at the City of Rocks near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 6, Folder 314)
    - View of a rock formations, probably at the City of Rocks near Silver City, New Mexico, circa 1904-1935; 1 photographic postcard (Box 6, Folder 315)